Xiating Cai (John)

Linkedin.com/in/JohnXiating

Phone: 0405 359 825 Email: john.xiating@gmail.com Portfolio: johnx.co

After travelling across the US, UK, South Asia and the east coast of Australia, and having worked in Shanghai and Sydney, I fell in love with Tasmania - a peaceful place to settle and create. I have experience in IT roles including Business Analysis, Services Operations, Customer Care, as well as experience across the Education and E-learning industry. I am currently living in Hobart, Tasmania. I am on a 500 Student Visa (until March 2021). Whilst waiting for the approval of my 485 Post-Study Work Visa (currently in progress) a Bridging-A Visa has been granted allowing me to work full time unrestricted.

Key Attributes

Interpersonal Skills: Effectively collaborated across different business functions (product, service, and tech team) during two years of IT consulting roles with large complex global corporations in Shanghai, one year of Customer IT Support role in Australia, and volunteer work in California (USA).

E-learning: Experienced in E-learning having gained two years of working experience as a science teacher for kids, one year of PASS leader (Web & Software Development) / Tutor at UTAS, two years of IT Consultant roles in online learning platform italki.com (Shanghai).

Initiative & Teamwork: Co-founded the Multi-Cultural Club, an active University society; Started up the <u>Virtual-study Hub</u> project to help students to study online during the COVID-19 time; Delivered award-winning team projects including GovHack 2020 and UHack 2019.

Work Experience

IT Helpdesk Support | Techbyte Solutions Launceston, Tasmania (May 2020 – Feb 2021)

- Utilised JavaScript, CSS3, Bootstrap, Facebook developer tools to create a business website for Techbyte Solutions (<u>techbyte.net.au</u>).
- Offered IT services include general IT support, web conferencing to businesses and individual customers with a range of understanding about technology.

Peer Assisted Study Session (PASS) Leader | University of Tasmania (Jan 2020 – Dec 2020)

- · Designed both online and offline study sessions (Web & Software Development) based on the students' feedback and needs. See session details at Google Folder.
- Facilitated and held online sessions for a range of different university students through MyLO student learning portal, Blackboard Collaborate, and Echo 360.

Residential Leader | University of Tasmania

(Jan 2020 - Dec 2020)

 Assisted residents on-campus to use the student learning & living portal to improve their academic and university living experience, organised student events with the student living team.

Riawunna Tutor | University of Tasmania

(Mar 2020 - May 2020)

• Utilised presentation, video, audio to deliver the Chinese language tutorial for students in the Riawunna program via MyLO, Blackboard Collaborate, and Zoom video conference.

Udemy Instructor | Udemy.com

(Jan 2019 - Jan 2020)

- Utilised animation, video to develop a content-driven video course for e-learners on Udemy.
 Reached 893 students who speak 25 languages across the world from 90 countries. See course details at Udemy: Learn Chinese From Scratch.
- Enrolled 110 courses through the Udemy student learning portal as a student; Used the instructor dashboard to communicate with students on the platform.

Teacher IT Support | italki Office Shanghai, China

(Jul 2015 - May 2018)

- Provided consulting and IT support for online language teachers worldwide, posted monthly teacher newsletters and guides to 4000+ teachers on the platform.
- Undertook customer satisfaction research and data analysis through the ticketing system to improve the new teacher onboarding experience and student learning experience.

Volunteer Experience and Projects

Web Developer & Content Creator | Multi-Cultural Club, Tasmania (Jun

(Jun 2020 - Present)

- · Co-Founded Multi-Cultural Club, utilised HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, and Bootstrap to create a static, informational website (mcctas.com.au) that met the needs of the society.
- Utilised Adobe Creative Suite to capture and edit photos, images, videos for the events recording, marketing, logo, and poster design.

Digital Marketing Assistance | GovHack, Australia

(Oct 2020 – Dec 2020)

- Mapped the user journey on the govhack.org to help the development of the prototype site.
- Researched WordPress themes and plugins for govhack.org to improve site accessibility.

Front-end Web Developer | Engineering Heritage Tasmania, Australia (Jul 2020 – Oct 2020)

• Developed enhancements to the <u>EHTAS</u> website application (map tours) as discussed with the client. Created <u>guide documents</u> and <u>video guides</u> to assist members with ranges of technical knowledge.

Project Leader | GovHack Launceston, Tasmania

(Aug 2020 - Aug 2020)

 Created the Heritage Hunt project concept, led and collaborated the team won three awards in <u>GovHack 2020</u>. Designed the UI and improved the prototype for the <u>Heritage Hunt app</u>.
 See project details <u>here</u>.

Project Leader | UHack Launceston, Tasmania

(Aug 2019 - Sep 2019)

- · Created the Plastic Free Tasmania project, led the team "No Plus" won the 3rd prize in the Student Division in UHack 2019 Competition.
- Presented a pitch that highlighted the plastic problem and the solution of "Plastic Currency".

Education

The University of Tasmania – Master of Information Management and Systems

March 2019 - December 2020

The University of Taizhou (Eastern China) – Bachelor of Physics (Teacher Education)

September 2008 – June 2012

Referees

Dr. Kathy French PASS Program Coordinator

University of Tasmania Email: kr.french@utas.edu.au Ph: 61 3 6226 5546

Sally Fuglsang Peer Program, Leadership and Volunteering Team Leader

University of Tasmania Email: sally.fuglsang@utas.edu.au Ph: +61 3 6226 1902

Jacob Workman Head, Student Living Communities (North & Northwest)

University of Tasmania Email: jacob.workman@utas.edu.au Ph: +61 3 6324 3014

Winyu Chinthammit Degree Coordinator, Human Interface Technology (HIT Lab AU)

University of Tasmania Email: winyu.chinthammit@utas.edu.au Ph: 61 3 6324 3975

Mark Smith Managing Director

Techbyte Solutions Email: mark@techbyte.net.au Ph: 61 3 6312 5190